Christopher Makarem

christopher.makarem@iocscan.io • christopher-makarem.me

Engineering undergrad with 2+ years of experience in systems and hardware design with strong focus on security seeking an opportunity to solve complex and interesting problems in the field of hardware/firmware security.

EDUCATION

University of California, Los Angeles

Henry Samueli School of Engineering
Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering

GPA: 3.02

Expected Graduation: March 2019

SKILLS

Languages: Java, C++, C, PERL (limited)

Scripting: Python, PowerShell, Bash, JavaScript

Principles: DHCP, IPv6, 6to4 tunneling, DNSSEC,

Virtual networking, VPN (all types)

Web Apps: NodeJS, Angular, React, Bootstrap

Environments: Active Directory (MAC and Windows)

LServices: ADFS, ADCS, WDS, S4B, SSL VPN

SharePoint, Exchange, Cisco CME

Tools: Wireshark, Logstash, Fiddler, NXLog, Regular Expressions

EXPERIENCE

Security Analyst (SAII - SAIII)

The DigiTrust Group

Santa Monica, CA October 2017 – Present

- Identified and classified key threats to client's network environments through log collection and aggregation to allow the support of new hardware devices contributing to increased client retention
 - Created PowerShell scripts to compile and standardize different log formats
 - Performed extensive DFIR research on network traffic patterns and user behavior
- Crafted information visuals in Elastic's Kibana to improve DFIR research and Health Check reports
- Wrote JavaScript functions to automate event handling for Security Analysts, reducing click volume and increasing productivity and turnaround time on event processing

Help Desk Technician Century City, CA

The Broad Foundation/Family Office Financial Services

October 2016 – September 2017

- Created custom PowerShell GUI tool for automatic user provisioning and migration to improve efficiency
- Deployed ADFS to facilitate MFA for end users, while ensuring in office security by restricting access to publicly accessible terminals such as conference rooms and phone booths
- Created custom SharePoint search page and URI handler to provide a more refined search for our SharePoint sites that allowed for improvements to refinement and specificity

Systems Administration Intern

Los Angeles, CA

American Computers and Engineers

June 2014 – September 2014; June 2015 – September 2015

- Developed Active Directory Environment for Windows based systems.
 - Hardened environment against standard attack vectors: Pass the hash, SMB exploits, DNS poisoning, privilege escalation via poor user access and segregation
- Deployed remote access and administration through DirectAccess and RADIUS server

PROJECTS

IOCSCAN.IO

IP address threat analysis

- Custom created web application that analyzes IP addresses to determine likelihood of malicious activity
- Designed custom heuristic algorithms to determine threat score and construct easy to interpret description

Machine Learning Optimization

Teaching a machine how to optimize

- Designed and implemented a neural network to construct a generalized optimization function to optimize a family of functions superior to standard monolithic algorithms
- Used in the design and model of antennas to maximize energy density and reduce interference